Register of the Guinea-Bissau Subject Collection, 1944-2001
Hoover Institution Archives
Guinea-Bissau Subject Collection,
1944-2001
XX783
2 manuscript boxes, 3 phonorecords (1 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Electronic bulletins, pamphlets, reports, communiques, clippings, and other printed matter, relating to revolutionary movements in Guinea-Bissau, especially the Partido Africano da Independ^encia da Guine e Cabo Verde, and to post-independence political, social and economic conditions.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Partido Africano da Independencia da Guine e Cabo Verde.; Guinea-Bissau--History--Revolution, 1963-1974.; Guinea-Bissau--Politics and government--1974-; Guinea-Bissau.; Africa.; Phonorecords.
Series Description
- SUBJECT FILE, 1972-1994 (Box 1)
  Brochure, fact sheet, pamphlet and printed matter relating to economic, political, religious and social conditions in Guineau-Bissau
- REVOLUTIONARY MOVEMENTS, 1960-1994 (Box 1)
  Articles, brochures, clippings, communiques, minutes of meetings, newsletters, pamphlets, printed matter, program and report relating to the revolutionary movements in Guinea-Bissau.
- AUDIO-VISUAL FILE, 1966 (Record cabinet)
  Three phonorecords.
Container List
See card catalog for increments that may have been received after December 1994
- SUBJECT FILE, 1972-1994
  - General (Box 1)
- REVOLUTIONARY MOVEMENTS, 1960-1994 Partido Africano da Independencia da Guine e das Ilhas do Cabo Verde (PAIGC)
  - General (Box 1)
    - Clippings and articles
    - Communiques
      - 1960-1965
      - 1970-1972
      - 1973
      - 1974-1976
  - Cabral, Amilcar. Includes speeches by Cabral and an article, 1973, relating to Cabral's assassination
  - Education. Elementary school textbooks
  - Foreign relations
    - Guinea
    - Senegal
  - Politics and government. Speeches from the Party congresses
  - Uniao Democratica das Mulheres da Guine-Bissau
- AUDIO-VISUAL FILE, 1966
  - Phonorecords. "Uma Cartucheira Cheia de Cancoes." Three records (Record-cabinet Record cabinet)
- Incremental Materials (Box 2:)
  This addition to the collection has not yet been described. Please let the Hoover Institution Archives know if you would like to see this material described.